<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Office 365 Tips to Improve Productivity - GitBit</title>
        <link>http://gitbit.org/</link>
        <description>Over 70% of Fortune 500 companies have migrated to Microsoft Office 365. Learn the latest tips to maximize your ROI.</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 12:23:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Feed for Node.js</generator>
        <image>
            <title>Office 365 Tips to Improve Productivity - GitBit</title>
            <url>http://gitbit.org/assets/gitbit/gitbit-icon-1200x1200.png</url>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>All rights reserved 2018, John L. Gruber</copyright>
        <category>Office 365</category>
        <category>Technology</category>
        <category>Microsoft</category>
        <atom:link href="http://gitbit.org/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[First Look at New Office Suite]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/first-look-at-new-office-suite</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/first-look-at-new-office-suite</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Microsoft Office is getting a new look. The updates are part of Microsoft’s new Fluent UI design. The fluent experience is designed to give a more natural feel across all devices giving you the same design on web, desktop, tablets, and televisions. Inspired by “The Three C’s”: customer, context, and]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>First Look at New Office Suite</h1><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-showing-fluent-ui.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook showing Fluent UI"></p><p>Microsoft Office is getting a new look. The updates are part of Microsoft&#x2019;s new Fluent UI design. The fluent experience is designed to give a more natural feel across all devices giving you the same design on web, desktop, tablets, and televisions. Inspired by &#x201C;The Three C&#x2019;s&#x201D;: customer, context, and control, Microsoft has listened to customers and found they want a simple but powerful productivity suite. Microsoft recognized context to be a major factor in designing the new simple yet powerful Fluent UI.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-ui-update-video.jpeg" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office UI update Video"></p><p>The new design has minimal color to prevent distraction and help you stay focused on your work. The new icons are similar to Office 2016 icons but have higher quality resolution with less contrasting colors.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;It&#x2019;s simpler and I feel like I can open it and immediately get my bearings and move forward. Not a lot of extra information. The tasks are obvious on this screen.&#x201D;</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-ui-icons-evolution.jpeg" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office UI Icons Evolution"></p><p>Microsoft has given you the ability to expand back to the classic ribbon using the drop-down arrow to the far right of the screen. You can quickly go back and forth if they prefer the extra screen space of the new Fluent UI while still needing the full ribbon for certain times.</p><blockquote>&#x201C;I like the extra space. What I do find is that the feature to toggle it off/on is helpful because occasionally I can&#x2019;t figure out (quickly) where something went.&#x201D;</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-expand-to-class-ribbon.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook Expand to Class Ribbon"></p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/web-version-of-word-with-fluen.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Web Version of Word with Fluent UI"></p><p>Microsoft is adding a new Coming Soon toggle switch to the Office apps. Much like the Office 365 Release Track, the Coming Soon toggle can be used to quickly add or remove new functionality before they&#x2019;re released to the public. The support documentation states the following:</p><blockquote>Occasionally, we&#x2019;ll release a new feature in Outlook that changes the look, feel, or functionality of Outlook. Coming Soon gives you a window of time to try these changes on your own schedule, learn about them, and share feedback with us before the changes are released to all customers.</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-coming-soon-toggle-swit.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office Coming Soon Toggle Switch"></p><p>Updates will be slowly rolled out across the web, Windows, and Apple Office apps. <a href="http://gitbit.org/apps/onedrive">OneDrive</a> on the web was the first Office 365 app to receive the Fluent UI. The re-design will be more slow and methodical than previous major releases, for example, the original Office ribbon.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-office-fluent-ui.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Office Fluent UI"></p><p>Microsoft has been transitioning from providing different apps for collaboration and productivity to integrating collaboration directly where you work. Part of the new Fluent UI is a redesign to comments and collaborating directly in Office documents. The new comment UI provide less contrast from your document to provide the comments you need while not distracting you from your work.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-with-comments.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office with Comments"></p>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/first-look-at-new-office-suite-1200x900.jpg" length="86668" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Live Video Broadcasts in Office 365 – In Development]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/live-video-broadcasts-in-office-365--in-development</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/live-video-broadcasts-in-office-365--in-development</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 16 Jun 2018 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Microsoft has begun development on live video broadcasting for Office 365. Live video broadcasting refers to online streaming media simultaneously recorded and broadcast in real time to the viewer. It’s referred to as streaming. The new feature will be included in Microsoft Stream, Office 365’s vide]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Live Video Broadcasts in Office 365 &#x2013; In Development</h1><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-stream-on-all-device.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Stream on all devices"></p><p>Microsoft has begun development on live video broadcasting for Office 365. Live video broadcasting refers to online streaming media simultaneously recorded and broadcast in real time to the viewer. It&#x2019;s referred to as streaming. The new feature will be included in <a href="http://gitbit.org/apps/stream">Microsoft Stream</a>, Office 365&#x2019;s video hosting app.</p><p>Microsoft has said the following on the first update:</p><blockquote>Live event broadcasting [will be] available in Microsoft Stream. Host and watch live broadcasts in Stream or watch them in Yammer and Teams.</blockquote><p>Once released, Office 365 users will have the ability to schedule and host live event broadcasts in Microsoft Stream. Microsoft Stream is expected to be updated in <strong>July 2018</strong>.</p><section><h2 id="licensing">Licensing</h2><p>Microsoft Stream is currently available to Office 365 users with the following licenses:</p><ul><li>Office 365 Enterprise E1</li><li>Office 365 Enterprise E3</li><li>Office 365 Enterprise E5</li><li>Office 365 A1</li><li>Office 365 A3</li><li>Office 365 A5</li><li>Office 365 F1</li><li>Stream Plan 1</li><li>Stream Plan 2</li></ul><p>Microsoft hasn&#x2019;t announced what plans will include live video broadcasting.</p></section><section><h2 id="azure-media-services">Azure Media Services</h2><p>Microsoft Stream is built on Azures Media Services which already has live video. While not announced, we can expect Microsoft stream to have similar features to Azure Media Services:</p><ul><li>Just-in-time AES encryption and PlayReady DRM technology</li><li>Direct integration with Content Delivery Network for automatic provisioning</li><li>Scalability to handle all audience sizes</li><li>Dynamic manifest manipulation for trimming and rendition filtering</li><li>Full cloud DVR workflow capabilities</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="history">History</h2><ul><li><strong>August 2017</strong>: Microsoft announced they were planning the update.</li><li><strong>December 2017</strong>: Microsoft announced the update was moving off the backlog and beginning development.</li><li><strong>June 2017</strong>: Microsoft added the update to the Office 365 roadmap with a planned deployment of July 2018.</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="future-updates">Future Updates</h2><p>After updating Microsoft Stream, live video functionality will be deployed in other Office 365 apps including <a href="http://gitbit.org/apps/yammer">Yammer</a> and <a href="http://gitbit.org/apps/microsoft-teams">Teams</a>. Microsoft said the following about Yammer:</p><blockquote>Allow users to host and drive conversations through live townhall events, broadcasted directly on Yammers feed using Stream.</blockquote><p>Microsoft expects to begin rolling out updates to Yammer and Teams in the 4th quarter of 2018.</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/live-video-broadcasts-in-office-365--in-development-1200x900.jpg" length="83079" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[8 Updates to Help Migrate and Collaborate between Skype and Teams]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/8-updates-to-help-migrate-and-</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/8-updates-to-help-migrate-and-</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jun 2018 19:47:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Microsoft is in the process of rolling out several major updates to the way businesses will communicate using Office 365. The updates are designed around improving the migration from Skype for Business to Microsoft Teams. While less than a year-old Microsoft made a bold statement that Microsoft Team]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>8 Updates to Help Migrate and Collaborate between Skype and Teams</h1><p>Microsoft is in the process of rolling out several major updates to the way businesses will communicate using Office 365. The updates are designed around improving the migration from Skype for Business to Microsoft Teams. While less than a year-old Microsoft made a bold statement that Microsoft Teams will replace Skype for Business. Microsoft Teams is a major game changer across many organizations. The latest updates to Microsoft Office 365 will allow a slower batch or champion style deployment that will give users backward compatibility and allow IT administrators to migrate to the new app out in phases reducing the IT burden.</p><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--skype-for-bus">Microsoft Teams &amp; Skype for Business Admin Center</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Feature ID</p></td><td><p>26982</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Description</p></td><td><p>The new&#xA0;Microsoft Teams &amp; Skype for Business&#xA0;Admin Center will provide you&#xA0;a&#xA0;unified&#xA0;experience to manage Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business.&#xA0;We&#x2019;re&#xA0;delivering&#xA0;additional functionality,&#xA0;end-to-end&#xA0;insights,&#xA0;and&#xA0;the&#xA0;ability&#xA0;to manage&#xA0;Teams&#xA0;settings on a user level.&#xA0;&#xA0;</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Status</p></td><td><p>Rolling Out</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>While still being rolled out, I haven&#x2019;t seen a link to the new Microsoft Teams &amp; Skype for Business Admin Center in the Office 365 admin center. I&#x2019;ve been able to access the new admin center by navigating to <a href="https://admin.teams.microsoft.com">https://admin.teams.microsoft.com</a> across multiple tenants. </p><p>After becoming comfortable in the new Admin center be sure to navigate to <strong>Org-wide settings -&gt; Teams upgrade</strong> and updating your <strong>Coexistence mode</strong> from <strong>Legacy</strong> to <strong>Islands</strong>.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-and-skype-for-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business Admin Center"></p><p>While Microsoft has <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoftteams/upgrade-and-coexistence-of-skypeforbusiness-and-teams">documented</a> more modes that we can expect to see shortly, Islands is the most current configuration.</p><p>Microsoft has said the following regarding Islands mode:</p><blockquote>Islands mode comes with one-way temporary interoperability that allows chat interoperability from Teams to Skype for Business when the following conditions are met:The Teams user is homed at, and enabled for, Skype for Business Online.The Skype for Business user has never used Teams (or isn&#x2019;t licensed for Teams).This mode is helpful when you want users who are primarily using Teams to connect with other users in the organization who are still using Skype for Business only.After the users who previously used only Skype for Business start to use Teams, all their chats from other Teams users will arrive in Teams. This switches these users to islands mode. From that point, they must keep running Teams to ensure they stay connected with the other Teams users in the organization. - <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoftteams/upgrade-and-coexistence-of-skypeforbusiness-and-teams">Microsoft</a></blockquote><p>While some admins are reporting integrated connectivity between Skype for Business and Microsoft Teams for chat while in legacy mode, the setting may be blocking the connectivity within your tenant including calling, meetings, and other collaboration features.</p><p>Microsoft does warn admins that coexistence is more complex than a simple cutover migration to Microsoft Teams. Islands mode allows an organization to conduct a proof of concept (PoC) of Teams and slowly migrate users from Skype for Business to Microsoft Teams. Islands mode doesn&#x2019;t allow a user to go back to Skype for Business and still communicate from Skype for Business to Microsoft Teams users. There is a workaround where an admin can remove Microsoft Teams licensing for the user. This drawback may be cause for concern for some organizations, each organization will need to weigh the value of migrating to Microsoft Teams prior to a more complete collaboration mode that I expect will be coming shortly.</p></section><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--skype-for-bus">Microsoft Teams &amp; Skype for Business Integration</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Feature ID</p></td><td><p>24190</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Description</p></td><td><p>This is one of the SfB messaging capabilities coming to Teams that enables a Teams user to chat with other users who are using Skype for business (online or on-prem). This requires Teams user&apos;s account to be hosted online.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Status</p></td><td><p>Launched</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Microsoft has launched a recent update to allow Microsoft Teams users to communicate with Skype for Business users. The new integration between the two apps will make it easier for users to migrate while still collaborating with colleagues that are still using Skype for Business. The new integration functionality will allow organizations to deploy Microsoft Teams to champions or specific departments prior to a full-scale deployment.</p><p>Microsoft Teams users will see the Skype icon next to a person&#x2019;s name in the chat view. This icon indicates the user is still using Microsoft Skype for Business.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-with-skype-for.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams with Skype for Business Integration"></p><p>Microsoft Teams will also warn your users in the Messages Header of a chat conversation that some functionality will not be possible between Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business Users. The loss of functionality is to be expected because Skype handles documents and other integrations differently. Since Microsoft is planning to retire Skype for Business I wouldn&#x2019;t anticipate a future update to make cross-app collaboration perfect.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-warning-about-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams warning about Skype features"></p><p>The Skype icon will also be seen in Windows 10 notifications (that appear in the bottom right hand corner when Microsoft Teams is not your active app).</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/windows-10-notification-with-m.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Windows 10 notification with Microsoft Teams and Skype integration"></p><p>The below screenshot is showing two separate users communicating across Skype for Business and Microsoft Teams. On the left, Adam Tucker, is using Skype for Business in OWA. On the right, Aaron Wells is using Microsoft Teams. Chat is fast and simple across the apps without any issues.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-and-skype-for-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business chat integration"></p></section><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--unified-prese">Microsoft Teams &#x2013; Unified Presence</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Feature ID</p></td><td><p>24191</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Description</p></td><td><p>This is one of the SfB messaging capabilities coming to Teams that supports unified presence between Teams and Skype for Business.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Status</p></td><td><p>Rolling Out</p></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote>&#x201C;Presence states for users (i.e. available, busy or in a call) will now be aggregated between Teams and Skype for Business. This ensures that a user has a single presence state regardless of the app and the device they use. &#xA0;For this functionality, the underlying Skype for Business account that is connected to the Teams user needs to be hosted in Skype for Business online.&#x201D; &#x2013; <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/Microsoft-Teams-Blog/What-s-new-in-Microsoft-Teams-April-update/ba-p/179801">Microsoft</a></blockquote><p>Users in Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business can now see colleagues free/busy information across apps. The improved functionality will help users seamlessly migrate to Microsoft Teams and continue to work in a coordinated and professional manner.</p><p>Upon testing, availability status updated flawlessly from Skype for Business to Microsoft Teams. I had some issues when the availability status did not update in Skype when a user made a change in Microsoft Teams. I&#x2019;m sure any issues are related to my test tenant or will be resolved shortly through a patch. Be sure to test availability in your tenant and discuss any issues with leadership and users.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-and-skype-for-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams and Skype for Business integrate presence status"></p></section><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--out-of-office">Microsoft Teams - Out of Office Support</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Feature ID</p></td><td><p>24167</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Description</p></td><td><p>This is one of the SfB calling capabilities coming to Teams. This feature will allow users to set an Out of Office status and share that with others. This feature is targeted for availability by Q2 CY 2018.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Status</p></td><td><p>In development</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p>Expected to be deployed shortly, Microsoft Teams will be integrating Out of Office support. The new integration will help users migrate from Skype for Business, as well as, stay up-to-date on a colleague&#x2019;s status after migrating to Microsoft Teams.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-out-of-office.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams out of office"></p><p>One of the major factors in moving to Microsoft Teams is the one-to-many chat capabilities. IT should have a plan in place for scenarios where a key member of a team or project is out of the office. Two options are available depending on your organization:</p><ol><li>Make a public team available for each department. If most of the departments in your organization can have their team public, where any employee can join the chat, it&#x2019;s a straightforward way to make an entire team available for any unplanned out-of-office scenarios. HR &amp; Accounting may need to manage two teams, one public and another private.</li><li>If an organization would prefer to keep the department teams private and secured from other employees within your organization, a company should create an all company team. All employees can be a member of the team and a channel can be created for each department. If an employee ever wants to contact an entire team they can utilize the appropriate channel. PowerShell is provided at the bottom of this article to help facilitate the creation of an all company team.</li></ol></section><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--import-contac">Microsoft Teams - Import Contacts from Skype for Business</h2><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Feature ID</p></td><td><p>24244</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Description</p></td><td><p>This is one of the SfB messaging capabilities coming to Teams, providing the ability to import contacts from Skype for Business.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Status</p></td><td><p>Launched</p></td></tr></tbody></table><blockquote>&#x201C;We&#x2019;re importing your contact list from Skype for Business Online to Teams. Now, all your contacts and groups that you created in Skype for Business will show up in Teams under your contact list. To access your contacts, simply click on &#x201C;Chat&#x201D; in the left navigation and then on &#x201C;Contacts&#x201D;. Here, you can also add new contacts or create new contact groups.In this first step, only contacts from your organization will be imported. Federated contacts from outside your organization will be added at a later point.&#x201D; - <a href="https://techcommunity.microsoft.com/t5/Microsoft-Teams-Blog/What-s-new-in-Microsoft-Teams-April-update/ba-p/179801">Microsoft</a></blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-with-contacts.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams with contacts"></p><p>Personally, I haven&#x2019;t gained access to <strong>Contacts</strong> in Microsoft Teams and haven&#x2019;t had the opportunity to test the new integration. While contacts may be important to some, I haven&#x2019;t found a strong need for contacts in Microsoft Teams. In Microsoft Teams you can compose a new chat, begin typing a user&#x2019;s name and Microsoft Teams will auto-populate a list of all users in your environment.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-teams-autopopulated-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Teams auto-populated users"></p><p>Auto-population plus the Recent contacts list have made it quick and easy to communicate with everyone across the organization. While Teams works great without contacts, the added functionality will be a major benefit to some employees.</p></section><section><h2 id="remote-deployment-of-microsoft">Remote Deployment of Microsoft Teams</h2><p>Going almost unnoticed, Microsoft has released MSI installers for Microsoft Teams. This enables organizations to leverage System Center Configuration Manager, Group Policy, or any 3rd party distribution mechanisms for broad deployments of Microsoft Teams. Admins can download the installation bits in the following locations:</p><ul><li><a href="http://aka.ms/teams32bitmsi">Microsoft Teams 32-bit MSI installer</a></li><li><a href="http://aka.ms/teams64bitmsi">Microsoft Teams 64-bit MSI installer</a></li></ul><p>Target machines will require Windows 7, .NET 4.5, and 3 GB of disk space for the installation. For more information on the deployment view Microsoft&#x2019;s <a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/MicrosoftTeams/msi-deployment">documentation</a>.</p></section><section><h2 id="microsoft-teams--all-company-t">Microsoft Teams &#x2013; All Company team</h2><p>The following section is designed to assist you with creating an All Company team in Microsoft Teams. The team can then be used to communicate and collaborate with your entire organization. Unfortunately, the max number of members in a team is 2,500. If your organization is larger than 2,500 users, you cannot use a single team to communicate. Due to the one-to-many communication method of Microsoft Teams, I personally wouldn&#x2019;t recommend having a team larger than 1,000 members. Communication of over 1,000 employees is best implemented using SharePoint and/or Yammer.</p><p>Microsoft has documented a similar command shell:</p><ul><li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/MicrosoftTeams/scripts/powershell-script-sample-create-company-wide-team">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/MicrosoftTeams/scripts/powershell-script-sample-create-company-wide-team</a></li><li><a href="https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/MicrosoftTeams/company-wide-team-creation-powershell">https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/MicrosoftTeams/company-wide-team-creation-powershell</a></li></ul><p>To run the following commands, you must be able to connect to Azure AD &amp; Microsoft Teams using PowerShell. Connecting to Office 365 PowerShell with a user that has MFA enabled is more difficult. If you haven&#x2019;t connected to Office 365 PowerShell before and have MFA enabled, it&#x2019;s recommended to temporarily disable MFA or create a Global Admin without MFA for one-time use.</p><p class="no-spacing"># Beginning of Script</p><p class="no-spacing">param(</p><p class="no-spacing">    [Parameter(Mandatory=$true, HelpMessage=&quot;Name of team for the All Company Team (Recommended: Company&quot;)]</p><p class="no-spacing">    [System.String]$TeamName,</p><p class="no-spacing">    [Parameter(Mandatory=$true, HelpMessage=&quot;Username of a global admin account&quot;)]</p><p class="no-spacing">    [System.String]$GlobalAdminUsername,</p><p class="no-spacing">    [Parameter(Mandatory=$true, HelpMessage=&quot;Password of the global admin account&quot;)]</p><p class="no-spacing">    [System.String]$GlobalAdminPassword</p><p class="no-spacing">)</p><p class="no-spacing">$encryptedPassword = ConvertTo-SecureString -AsPlainText -Force -String $GlobalAdminPassword</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Install NuGet (Used to install Microsoft Teams module)&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">Install-PackageProvider -Name NuGet -MinimumVersion 2.8.5.201 -Force</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Install Azure AD PowerShell&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">Install-Module AzureAD -Force</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Install Microsoft Teams PowerShell&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">Install-Module MicrosoftTeams -Force</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Connect to Azure AD&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">$cred = New-Object -typename System.Management.Automation.PSCredential -argumentlist $GlobalAdminUsername, $encryptedPassword</p><p class="no-spacing">Connect-AzureAD -Credential $cred</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Connect to Microsoft Teams&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">$cred = New-Object -typename System.Management.Automation.PSCredential -argumentlist $GlobalAdminUsername, $encryptedPassword</p><p class="no-spacing">Connect-MicrosoftTeams -Credential $cred</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Get all Microsoft Office 365 Users&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">$Users = Get-AzureADUser -All $true</p><p class="no-spacing">$Users = $Users | ?{ $_.UserType -eq &apos;Member&apos; -and $_.AccountEnabled -eq $true -and $_.AssignedLicenses -ne $null }</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Verify you don&apos;t have over 2,500 users&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">if ($Users.Count -gt 2500) {</p><p class="no-spacing">    throw &quot;You have more than 2500 users. A team in Microsoft Teams cannot have over 2,500 users&quot;</p><p class="no-spacing">}</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Create Team&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">$Group = New-Team -DisplayName $TeamName -AccessType Public</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Adding users to team&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">foreach ($User in $Users) {</p><p class="no-spacing">    Write-Host &quot;  Adding $($User.UserPrincipalName) to team&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan    </p><p class="no-spacing">    Add-TeamUser -GroupId $Group.GroupId -Role Owner -User $User.UserPrincipalName.ToString()</p><p class="no-spacing">}</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Disconnect from AzureAD&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">Disconnect-AzureAD</p><p class="no-spacing">Write-Host &quot;Disconnect from Microsoft Teams&quot; -ForegroundColor Cyan</p><p class="no-spacing">Disconnect-MicrosoftTeams</p><p class="no-spacing"># END OF SCRIPT</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/8-updates-to-help-migrate-and--1200x900.jpg" length="109339" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Agile Teamwork with Office 365 Planner]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/agile-teamwork-with-office-365</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/agile-teamwork-with-office-365</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 15 May 2018 11:34:51 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[On December 1st, 1913 Henry Ford installed the first moving assembly line. It was brilliant. His innovation reduced the time it took to build a car from more than 12 hours to two hours and 30 minutes. Ford increased production and decreased costs. His plan moved the automobile from one station to th]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Agile Teamwork with Office 365 Planner</h1><p>On December 1st, 1913 Henry Ford installed the first moving assembly line. It was brilliant.&#xA0;His innovation reduced the time it took to build a car from more than 12 hours to two hours and 30 minutes.&#xA0;Ford increased production and decreased costs. His plan moved the automobile from one station to the next until it was complete. Today, the world is a lot faster. Many projects today follow the same design concepts, each person waiting their turn to work a project. Project management and overhead costs for projects is a constant struggle on projects.</p><p>Microsoft Planner uses a new model designed around teamwork. In Microsoft Planner, a team can work together while staying organized, assigning tasks, sharing files, and chat about the project directly in the app. The streamlined design gives project management and leadership clarity in the project without employees wasting time.</p><section><h2 id="rugby-teamwork--management">Rugby Teamwork &amp; Management</h2><p>In 1986 two rugby fans Hirotaka Takeuchi and Ikujiro Nonaka created an innovative approach to projects and teamwork. In this&#xA0;new<em>&#xA0;</em>approach the team &#x201C;tries to go the distance as a unit, passing the ball back and forth&#x201D;. Today, we call this agile project management framework&#xA0;<strong>Scrum</strong>.</p><p>Scrum is the leading agile development methodology, used by Fortune 500 companies around the world. It&#x2019;s a framework or a way of thinking about projects that help you stay organized and dynamic while not wasting time on project management. There&#x2019;s no better place to learn about SCRUM then the&#xA0;<a href="https://www.scrumalliance.org/why-scrum" target="_blank">SCRUM Alliance</a>.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/scrum-board.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="SCRUM Board"></p></section><section><h2 id="the-scrum-framework-in-30secon">The Scrum framework in 30&#xA0;seconds</h2><ul><li>A product owner creates a prioritized wish list called a product backlog.</li><li>During sprint planning, the team pulls a small chunk from the top of that wish list, a sprint backlog, and decides how to implement those pieces.</li><li>The team has a certain amount of time&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;a sprint (usually two to four weeks)&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;to complete its work, but it meets each day to assess its progress (daily Scrum).</li><li>Along the way, the ScrumMaster keeps the team focused on its goal.</li><li>At the end of the sprint, the work should be potentially shippable or show to a stakeholder.</li><li>The sprint ends with a sprint review and retrospective.</li><li>As the next sprint begins, the team chooses another chunk of the product backlog and begins working again.</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="scrum-vs-traditional-waterfall">Scrum vs Traditional Waterfall Project Management</h2><p>Scrums work a bit differently than your traditional project management; most organizations will use both due to the different needs of projects.</p><p>Scrums are recommended when a project&#x2019;s needs change and there are a lot of moving parts that can happen simultaneously. The Scrum framework allows different people to pick up tasks and work them independently. You can hit roadblocks while continuing in another area of the project. This flow is agile yet organized.</p><p>The traditional waterfall is great when a project must naturally move in a static linear fashion. For example, when building a server. First, the networking team must create the private network. Then the virtualization team can create the VMs. Then the Windows team installs the OS. Each team has to wait for the team before them completes before starting their tasks. While we could still use the Scrum framework, the more traditional tools of waterfall project management are helpful too.</p></section><section><h2 id="scrum-tools">Scrum Tools</h2><p>In Rugby, you barely have any equipment. Likewise, agile projects want a small dynamic tool-set that won&#x2019;t get in the way. Meet <strong>Microsoft Planner</strong>.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-planner-on-laptop-an.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Planner on laptop and smartphone"></p><p>Planner comes directly with your Office 365 subscription. Planner is Microsoft Office 365&#x2019;s task management app for teams. The app&#x2019;s design is based on the Scrum framework. </p><p>At the top level, you have&#xA0;<strong>plans</strong>.&#xA0;Each team or project can have its own plan. Plans are the highest level in the organizational structure of Microsoft Planner.<img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-planner--plans-view.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Planner - plans view"></p><p>Within a plan you have&#xA0;<strong>buckets</strong>.&#xA0;A bucket is a way to organize&#xA0;<strong>tasks</strong>. Tasks can move through the different buckets to show a status or you can use buckets to group the project into phases.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/plan-view-of-microsoft-planner.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Plan view of Microsoft Planner"></p><p>A task is a piece of work that must be completed. Tasks can move around the different buckets, assigned to different people, have comments, etc.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/task-view-in-microsoft-planner.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Task view in Microsoft Planner"></p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-get-started-with-a-simp">How to get Started with a Simple&#xA0;Plan</h2><p>Next, we&#x2019;re going through a straightforward way to use the Scrum framework and Planner. The most basic plan is a team to-do list. Open the Planner app and create a plan. It will automatically have a to-do bucket. From there you can add members and create tasks.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/simple-microsoft-planner-view-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Simple Microsoft Planner view with one bucket"></p><p>Team members will know what tasks are available to work because the task won&#x2019;t have an assignee. When a team member starts working a task, they should mark the task &#x2018;in progress&#x2019; and assign the task to themselves.</p><p>When the work&#x2019;s completed, they can mark the task completed and move on to the next task.</p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-add-team-members-to-a-p">How to Add Team Members to a Plan</h2><p>When on your plan page, click <strong>Members</strong> in the top right corner. Enter the name or email address in the <strong>Enter name to add a member</strong> text box. One of the best features of Microsoft Planner is the ability to add &#x2018;Guest Members&#x2019; to your plan for no additional cost! That way you can add partners, third-party consultants and customers directly to your plan.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/how-to-add-team-members-to-a-p.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="How to add team members to a plan"></p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-add-teammeetings">How to add Team&#xA0;Meetings</h2><p>You&#x2019;ve created your plan and added your members. Everyone&#x2019;s working tasks and things are going well. Things are moving quickly, and the team is growing, we&#x2019;ll need to start to discuss tasks in a daily or weekly meeting. During the meeting, you can pop open your plan and review everything quickly. </p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/quick-view-of-a-task-in-micros.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Quick view of a task in Microsoft Planner"></p><p>Each task has a few quick bits of information to show if the task is <strong>in progress, when the task is due, and how many of the subtasks have already been complete</strong>.</p><p>Each bucket has a <strong>Show Completed </strong>section where you can view closed tasks too. Open the &#x2018;Show Completed&#x2019; section to discuss completed tasks.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/quick-view-of-a-bucket-in-micr.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Quick view of a bucket in Microsoft Planner"></p></section><section><h2 id="quality-assurance">Quality Assurance</h2><p>Adding Q&amp;A testing is easy too. Create a new bucket called &#x2018;Q&amp;A&#x2019;. When a team member completes a task that needs a second person to review, they&#x2019;ll move the task to the Q&amp;A bucket. Someone from Q&amp;A can pick up the task and perform there testing prior to closing the ticket. If QA fails, they can add a comment and move the task back to the To-do bucket.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/plan-with-two-buckets-in-micro.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Plan with two buckets in Microsoft Planner"></p></section><section><h2 id="tier-2-support-required">Tier 2 Support Required!</h2><p>Now our team has grown. We have new interns that can handle most things but occasionally, they need assistance. Now that we have two tiers we create another bucket called Tier 2. When an intern cannot complete a task, they can add their notes to the task and move it over to the Tier 2 bucket. Voila!</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/plan-view-with-three-buckets-i.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Plan view with three buckets in Microsoft Planner"></p></section><section><h2 id="waiting-onparts">Waiting on&#xA0;Parts</h2><p>Now, we need to add hardware to the project. After the parts are ordered a task can be created to keep the team updated on the order status. We don&#x2019;t want to clog up the To-do bucket with tasks that cannot be worked. We&#x2019;ll need to create a new bucket called &#x2018;On-Hold&#x2019;. Then the task can be placed in the On-Hold bucket. Once the parts arrive and the task can be worked we&#x2019;ll add a comment to the task and move the task to the proper bucket.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/4-buckets-in-microsoft-planner.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="4 buckets in Microsoft Planner plan view"></p></section><section><h2 id="summary">Summary</h2><p>Microsoft Planner is built right into Office 365. If you&#x2019;re subscribed to Office 365 you can start right away.&#xA0;The Planner app is lightweight and dynamic. You can make it fit your team and goals, not the other way around.</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/agile-teamwork-with-office-365-1200x900.jpg" length="217070" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[4 Steps to Being More Productive Using Microsoft To-Do]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/4-steps-to-being-more-producti</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/4-steps-to-being-more-producti</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 17:43:04 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Microsoft To-Do is one of the latest apps included in Office 365. It’s a simple to-do list that makes it easy to plan your day. Whether it’s for work, school or home, To-Do will help you increase your productivity and decrease your stress levels. To-Do has a unique way to organize your tasks into li]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>4 Steps to Being More Productive Using Microsoft To-Do</h1><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-todo-my-day-view.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft To-Do My Day View"></p><blockquote>The list is the origin of culture. It&#x2019;s part of the history of art and literature. What does culture want? To make infinity comprehensible. It also wants to create order&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;not always, but often. And how, as a human being, does one face infinity? How does one attempt to grasp the incomprehensible? Through lists&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;Umberto Eco</blockquote><p>Microsoft To-Do is one of the latest apps <strong>included in Office 365</strong>. It&#x2019;s a simple to-do list that makes it easy to plan your day. Whether it&#x2019;s for work, school or home, To-Do will help you <strong>increase your productivity</strong> and decrease your stress levels. To-Do has a unique way to organize your tasks into lists, then combining those lists into a <strong>My Day</strong> view to clear the clutter and keep you organized.</p><section><h2 id="criteria-for-choosing-a-todo-a">Criteria for Choosing a To-Do App</h2><p>Before any decision, it&#x2019;s important to lay out the criteria needed. Personally, I had 5 requirements for selecting a to-do app.</p><ul><li><strong>Security</strong>: While you should never store passwords in your to-do app, security is still a top concern. To-Do uses encryption and stores your data in highly safe data centers managed by Microsoft.</li><li><strong>Compliance: Depending on your requirements, you may not need to be compliant</strong>. Microsoft To-Do integrates into Outlook Tasks so any compliance features that your administrator has set extends to Microsoft To-Do.</li><li><strong>Access Anywhere: </strong>Being able to access and update your to-do list on the go is more important than ever. To-Do syncs with your phone and computer, so you can access your to-dos from anywhere in the world. You can quickly add, organize, and schedule your to-dos while you&#x2019;re on the go.</li><li><strong>Automation</strong>: For power users, automation becomes the key to productivity. Microsoft has just released a connector for Microsoft Flow / To-Do integration. The new integration between Flow and To-Do is going to have a tremendous affect on automating and organizing your To-Do list.</li><li><strong>Ease of Use</strong>: Any to-do app needs to be simple, fast, and easy to use. To-Do is designed with &#x201C;simple mechanics&#x201D;. &#x201C;We designed To-Do so it&#x2019;s features tend to only show up as the customer needs them.&#x201D; &#x2013; Simon Chan</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="introduction-to-microsoft-todo">Introduction to Microsoft To-Do</h2><p>To-Do is a simply yet powerful app to help you organize. When using Office 365, To-Do comes packaged with your service. The tasks are all synced back to your Outlook tasks for a simple, secure, and integrated experience. What&#x2019;s truly unique about To-Do is the simply My Day view. You can sort and group all your tasks logically, then on a daily basis add the tasks to your My Day view. This simple design helps you stay focused while being able to stay organized.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/42-stars-for-todo-windows-stor.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="4.2 Stars for To-Do Windows Store Review"></p><h3>Microsoft To-Do has a Simple Break Down for Organization</h3><ol><li><strong>Lists</strong>: A way to organize tasks by different groups, for example work or personal.</li><li><strong>Tasks</strong>: A item on your to-do list. Each task can have notes, reminders and be set reoccurring.</li><li><strong>Steps</strong>: Also known as a sub-task, steps help break down tasks into smaller more manageable chunks.</li><li><strong>My Day</strong>: A special view that you can add tasks to organize your daily to-do list across your lists clearing the clutter of less important tasks.</li></ol></section><section><h2 id="1-create-lists-and-tasks-for-e">1. Create Lists and Tasks for Everything</h2><blockquote>Your mind is for having ideas, not holding them&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;David Allen</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/todo-lists-screenshot.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="To-Do Lists Screenshot"></p><p>David Allen is the master of to-do lists and has dedicated his life to helping people apply order to chaos and get more done. David&#x2019;s first recommendation would be to jot everything down. Get all the tasks out of your head. Once the tasks are out of your head you can breathe easier knowing exactly what needs to be done and not forget a thing.</p><p>Every to-do app has two goals: improve productivity and relieve stress and Microsoft To-Do&#x2019;s flexible design can help you do just that. Quickly create lists to organize tasks then create tasks in each list. Stay organized, without unnecessary complexity. As a task may grow to need multiple steps, you can add steps to the tasks. Simple, organized, and fast.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/task-view-in-microsoft-todo.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Task view in Microsoft To-Do"></p></section><section><h2 id="2-prioritize-daily">2. Prioritize Daily</h2><blockquote>Start by doing what&#x2019;s necessary; then do what&#x2019;s possible, and suddenly you are doing the impossible.&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;Francis of Assisi</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/todo-my-day-every-day-is-a-fre.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="To-Do My Day. Every day is a fresh start. Focus on what you want to accomplish today with My Day."></p><p>Microsoft To-Do has a unique design based on My Day. The <strong>My Day</strong> view is used to clear the clutter from your list of today&#x2019;s actionable items. Start every day by reviewing your lists and moving priority tasks to the My Day view. The <strong>My Day list is the heart of Microsoft To-Do and what makes it truly unique</strong>. It&#x2019;s designed around clearing the clutter and prioritizing what&#x2019;s important for the day. At the end of each day review your list and check off your completed tasks.</p></section><section><h2 id="3-ask-for-help">3. Ask for Help</h2><blockquote>Get the master of arithmetic to show you how to square a triangle.&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;Leonardo da Vinci</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/leonardo-da-vincis-500yearold-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Leonardo da Vinci&#x2019;s 500-year-old to-do list there were a ton of to-do items where he planned to ask others how things work."></p><p>In Leonardo da Vinci&#x2019;s 500-year-old to-do list there were a ton of to-do items where he planned to ask others how things work. Leonardo&#x2019;s relentless pursuit of knowledge is a lesson for us all. Add tasks to follow-up with people, remind yourself to spark a conversation, and don&#x2019;t be afraid to ask someone else to help when you&#x2019;re feeling overwhelmed. The best organizations work because people work as a team.</p></section><section><h2 id="4-create-a-bucket-list">4. Create a Bucket List</h2><blockquote>My mission in life is not merely to survive, but to thrive; and to do so with some passion, some compassion, some humor, and some style.&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;Maya Angelou</blockquote><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/homer-simpsons-bucket-list.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Homer Simpsons Bucket List"></p><p>We all have life goals. From getting more organized to finding more time to annoy our wives. Put all these long-term goals in a list and review them daily, weekly, or monthly. When possible, create a to-do item to get yourself closer to your dreams. <strong>Setup reoccurring tasks to remind yourself to spend 15 minutes a day learning a new language. </strong>Make your dreams a reality, make them a priority, and let your to-do app help you stay on top of it.</p></section><section><h2 id="the-future-of-todo">The Future of To-Do</h2><p>Microsoft To-Do is a rapidly growing and evolving app. Microsoft has promised to decommission Wunderlist once To-Do has all its best features. Below is a quick list of features we can expect from To-Do in the future:</p><ol><li>Folders&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;To organize lists.</li><li>Sharing&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;To share a to-do list or task with others.</li><li>Tags&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;To help organize across lists.</li><li>Comments&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;To keep more complex tasks moving forward and organized.</li><li>Integrations&#x200A;&#x2014;&#x200A;To integrate with everything!</li></ol><p>To-Do has the Wunderlist team dedicated to its development and they&#x2019;re adding features quickly. Keep up with changes and make your voice heard by using <a href="https://todo.uservoice.com/">https://todo.uservoice.com/</a>.</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/4-steps-to-being-more-producti-1200x900.jpg" length="49872" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Power Users Guide to Outlook 2016 Search]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/power-users-guide-to-outlook-2</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/power-users-guide-to-outlook-2</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 19:08:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Despite new apps like Slack, and Microsoft Teams email is still one of the most common and fastest growing platforms for communication. Mailboxes continue to expand, and people are receiving more emails per day year over year. The rapid growth of mailboxes is why Microsoft offers 50 GB mailboxes for]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>Power Users Guide to Outlook 2016 Search</h1><p>Despite new apps like Slack, and Microsoft Teams email is still one of the most common and fastest growing platforms for communication. Mailboxes continue to expand, and people are receiving more emails per day year over year. The rapid growth of mailboxes is why Microsoft offers 50 GB mailboxes for all customers. Enterprise customers (E3 &amp; E5) receive 100 GB mailboxes with an archive mailbox with unlimited size. </p><p>Email usage isn&#x2019;t the only reason for mailbox expansion. Regulations, for example HIPAA, have required many organizations to retain all emails for several years. As time continues, the growing requirements for data storage by regulators will continue to expand.</p><p>While Microsoft Office 365 handles most concerns, notably storage and security, <strong>administrators and end-users face one large challenge: search</strong>. Fortunately for Office 365 / Outlook ProPlus customers, Microsoft has built searching and indexing into Outlook. Outlook&#x2019;s search is fast, dynamic, and robust.</p><p>Tapping into the mailbox search features is one of the best ways to improve productivity. Search has the capability to search across folders and mailboxes. Once you&#x2019;ve mastered searching you may no longer have to waste time organizing your inbox. By leaving everything in the inbox and improving your search ability you&#x2019;ll be able to quickly find emails from certain people, with certain keywords, and find attachments without any unneeded sorting and organizing.</p><section><h2 id="introduction-to-outlook-search"><strong>Introduction to Outlook Search</strong></h2><p>Outlook 2016&#x2019;s search feature is located in the center of each page or pulled to the right.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/search-bar-in-outlook-2016.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Search Bar in Outlook 2016"></p><h3>Narrowing your Search</h3><p>The search will change depending on if you&#x2019;re in your inbox, calendar, people, or tasks folder. When located in your inbox, or any email folder, the search will have a drop-down box on the right-hand side to narrow your search by folder, mailbox, or everywhere.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-search-bar-with-mailbo.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook Search bar with mailbox filter drop down"></p><h3>Word Matching: Case Sensitivity &amp; Prefix Matching</h3><p>The search is intelligently designed. Type in a word or phrase and Outlook will search the subject, body, and other fields to find a match. Searches aren&#x2019;t case sensitive, so you don&#x2019;t need to worry about searching for words with upper and lower-case characters. Outlook&#x2019;s search includes a prefix matching system too. Searching for &#x201C;build&#x201D; will return other words like &#x201C;building&#x201D;.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-prefix-searching.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft prefix searching"></p><h3>Search Ribbon</h3><p>When you click on the Search textbox Microsoft will display the Search ribbon. In the search ribbon you can narrow your search by different fields and limit your search results.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-2016-search-ribbon.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook 2016 Search ribbon"></p><p>The ribbon is a fantastic way to limit your search. Use the ribbon if you can&#x2019;t find the email you&#x2019;re looking for after performing a keyword search. After clicking a button in the ribbon Outlook will automatically add the proper keywords to your search. Fill in the blanks and press<strong> Enter</strong> to limit your search.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/searching-using-keywords-in-th.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Searching using keywords in the search bar for Outlook 2016"></p></section><section><h2 id="search-keyword-table">Search Keyword Table</h2><p>Keywords is where we can really start to unlock the searches full potential. The search box has been integrated with a ton of search patterns and keywords to use. The easiest way to learn the keywords is by using the Search ribbon. When using the Search ribbon, the keywords will automatically be filled in on your behalf. After remembering some keywords, you can improve your search productivity and success using the keywords.</p><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Keyword</p></td><td><p>Example</p></td><td><p>Description</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>AND</p></td><td><p>Build AND server</p></td><td><p>Items containing both words but not necessarily in that order</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>NOT</p></td><td><p>NOT server</p></td><td><p>Items that don&#x2019;t contain the word</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>&#x201C;&#x201D;</p></td><td><p>&#x201C;server build&#x201D;</p></td><td><p>Items containing the exact phrase</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>From:&#x201D;&#x201D;</p></td><td><p>From:&#x201C;John&#x201D;</p></td><td><p>Items containing the word or phrase in the from field.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>hasattachment:</p></td><td><p>hasattachment:yes</p></td><td><p>Items that have or don&#x2019;t have an attachment.</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Attachments:</p></td><td><p>attachments:presentation.pptx</p></td><td><p>Items that have a particular attachment</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Subject:</p></td><td><p>Subject:server</p></td><td><p>Items with a word or phrase in the subject line</p></td></tr></tbody></table><p><em>NOTE: Keywords AND, NOT, and OR are case-sensitive. The must be all upper-case.</em></p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-perform-an-advanced-sea">How to Perform an Advanced Search</h2><p>You can use the <strong>Advanced Find</strong> feature for complex searches. Advanced searches are a great way to find emails when you know information in multiple fields but cannot find the item with a normal search.</p><p>Advanced Find can be found under the <strong>Search ribbon &gt; Search Tools &gt; Advanced Find&#x2026;</strong></p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/advanced-find-button-in-outloo.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Advanced Find button in Outlook search ribbon"></p><p>The Advanced Find box will have a ton of options for filtering and retrieving the exact item you&#x2019;re looking for.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/advanced-find-in-outlook-2016.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Advanced find in Outlook 2016"></p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-increase-the-search-res">How to Increase the Search Results in Outlook 2016</h2><p>By default, Outlook 2016 limits the number of searches returned when searching your mailbox. The default limit is set to 250. The limit is designed to improve search results speed. Outlook does have an option to return all items when you perform a search. While a bit slower, those that need to perform a lot of mailbox searches may find the change improves productivity.</p><h3>Default Search Result Limits in Outlook</h3><table><tbody><tr><td><p>Outlook Version</p></td><td><p>Default Limit</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Outlook 2016</p></td><td><p>250</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Outlook 2013</p></td><td><p>250</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Outlook 2010</p></td><td><p>200</p></td></tr><tr><td><p>Outlook 2007</p></td><td><p>200</p></td></tr></tbody></table><h3>Outlook 2016 Increase Search Results (Simple)</h3><ol><li>From Outlook go to <strong>File &gt; Options &gt; Search</strong>.</li><li>Uncheck <strong>Improve search speed by limiting the number of results shown</strong>.</li></ol><h3>Outlook 2016 Increase Search Results (Detailed)</h3><ol><li>From Outlook click the <strong>File</strong> button.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/file-button-in-outlook.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="File button in Outlook"></li><li>From the file menu, click <strong>Options</strong>. The options menu contains hundreds of settings that you can use to change how Outlook interacts. Microsoft has separated the options into different categories, mail, calendar, people, and tasks just to name a few. You&#x2019;ll find the section, or categories, listed on the left-hand side called the navigation pane.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/options-button-in-outlook-file.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Options button in Outlook File menu"></li><li>Click <strong>Search</strong> in the left navigation pane.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-options-with-search-bu.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook options with Search button circled"></li><li>From the Search menu you can update how searching and indexing functions. Microsoft has included several options including indexing, what&#x2019;s searched by default, and the limit to search results. To return all results when performing a search click <strong>Improve search speed by limiting the number of results shown</strong>.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-options-search-with-im.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook options search with Improve search speed by limiting the number of results shown circled"></li><li>After you uncheck the box click OK to save the settings. No reboot or Outlook restart required. Perform a search to verify the results are no longer limited.</li></ol></section><section><h2 id="how-to-fix-common-problems-wit">How to Fix Common Problems with Outlook Search</h2><p>Outlook search uses Microsoft&#x2019;s built-in indexing system. Simply put, every Outlook item is indexed into a local database on the computer, as well as, on the server for fast searching. Sometimes, the index can become corrupt or misconfigured and not return the items from Outlook.</p><h3>How to Verify Local Search Issues</h3><p>When you have an issue with searching, you&#x2019;ll want to verify if you have a local problem. Open Office 365&#x2019;s OWA (<a href="https://mail.office365.com">https://mail.office365.com</a>), login, and perform a search from OWA. OWA will use the server&#x2019;s indexes and won&#x2019;t rely on the local computer. If you find the items using OWA but can&#x2019;t find the item on your local Outlook, you have a local problem.</p><p>OWA&#x2019;s search is located in the top left corner of the webpage.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-365-owa-search-bar.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office 365 OWA search bar"></p><h3>How to Verify Indexing is Enabled for Outlook</h3><p>Outlook is added to the indexing by default. You can add or remove Microsoft Outlook from the Index by going to <strong>Outlook &gt; File &gt; Options &gt; Search &gt; Indexing Options</strong>.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-indexing-options.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook Indexing Options"></p><h3>How to Rebuild the Index</h3><p>After you verified Microsoft Outlook is being indexed, and you&#x2019;re having a local problem, the next step is rebuilding the index.</p><p>Go to<strong> Outlook &gt; File &gt; Options &gt; Search &gt; Indexing Options &gt; Advanced &gt; Rebuild.</strong></p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-indexing-options-advan.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook Indexing options advanced menu"></p><h3>Final Solution</h3><p>If you continue to have Outlook search issues your next step is calling your IT support, partner, or Microsoft to help.</p></section><section><h2 id="search-on-outlook-for-android-">Search on Outlook for Android &amp; iPhone</h2><p>Microsoft has recently improved the search on smartphones and tablets. If you&#x2019;re using the Outlook app on your device, you can find the search by clicking the magnifying glass in the menu.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-app-search-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook app search button"></p><p>After the search page opens you can use your keyword search just like Outlook on your desktop.</p><ul><li>In the top right corner, you can filter the search results by mailbox.</li><li>Right below the mailbox filter button is an attachment switch to filter by attachments.</li></ul><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-app-searching-screensh.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook app searching screenshot"></p><p>Can you think of any tips I missed? Share with me your favorites on Twitter <a href="https://twitter.com/gruberjl">@gruberjl</a> or <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/gruberjl/">LinkedIn</a>.</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/power-users-guide-to-outlook-2-1200x900.jpg" length="68229" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[12 Tips for Improving Productivity using OneNote]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/12-tips-for-improving-producti</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/12-tips-for-improving-producti</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 16:55:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[OneNote is a digital notebook that automatically backs up to Microsoft’s Office 365 cloud. Microsoft has developed apps for every device including Windows PC, Mac, iPhone, Android. OneNote notebooks can be shared with colleagues for real-time collaboration.]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>12 Tips for Improving Productivity using&#xA0;OneNote</h1><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenotequicktips.jpeg" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote-Quick-Tips"></p><section><h2 id="whats-onenote">What&#x2019;s OneNote?</h2><p>OneNote is a digital notebook that automatically backs up to Microsoft&#x2019;s Office 365 cloud. Microsoft has developed apps for every device including Windows PC, Mac, iPhone, Android. OneNote notebooks can be shared with colleagues for real-time collaboration.</p></section><section><h2 id="why-onenote">Why OneNote?</h2><p>OneNote allows you to capture just about anything. Type notes, record audio, create a quick sketch, add pictures, videos, and any other document. Then organize everything into notebooks, sections, and pages. OneNote can be as structured or as unstructured as you want it to be. And because all your notes are in the cloud, OneNote lets you switch devices and pick up right where you left off.</p><p>Last but certainly not least, integration! You can take note in OneNote while on a phone call, quickly add check-boxes turning the notes into a to-do list. Then, add an Outlook flag to remind you to follow up later. Or link an Outlook calendar appointment to a OneNote page and share the notes to everyone in the meeting. The possibilities are endless.</p></section><section><h2 id="1-create-a-quicknote">1. Create a Quick&#xA0;Note</h2><p>How often does this happen? How often does this happen? You&apos;re out to lunch and remember you need to call a customer and follow up on your last meeting. Quick notes are perfect for capturing a thought on one device such as your phone, and then retrieving it from another device, such has your computer when you&#x2019;re in the office.</p><p>Use Quick Notes to jot down any thoughts and ideas, just like sticky notes. Each Quick Note is instantly saved as a page in the <strong>Unfiled Notes</strong> section of the <strong>Quick Notes</strong> notebook.</p><p><em>Quick Notes are the electronic equivalent of little yellow sticky notes. When you create a Quick Note, it&#x2019;s saved immediately as a section in &lt;your name&gt; Notebook. OneNote uses both the Quick Notes and &lt;your name&gt; Notebook to sync your notes to OneDrive. For this reason, don&#x2019;t rename the &lt;your name&gt; Notebook or the Quick Notes section.</em></p><h3>How to create a quick note on smartphones</h3><p><em>The following instructions are for an Android smartphone but are similar on iPhone. If you have any difficulty with your iPhone please let me know if the comments and I&#x2019;ll write up instructions.</em></p><p>Once you download the <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.office.onenote&amp;hl=en" target="_blank">OneNote Android app</a> and login to your Office 365 account you can begin using OneNote on your smartphone anytime, anywhere. OneNote for Android has <strong>widgets</strong> for creating a new <strong>text</strong> note, <strong>audio</strong> note, and <strong>picture</strong> note. To use any of these widgets, simply tap and drag them to your phone&#x2019;s home screen.</p><p>From your Android home screen, tap and hold until the management view appears. Click WIDGETS.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/add-onenote-quick-note-to-andr.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Add OneNote Quick Note to Android"></p><p>Scroll down until you find the <strong>OneNote</strong> app. Scroll through the different widgets and add them to your home screen!</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/add-onenote-to-android.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Add OneNote to Android"></p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/android-with-onenote-quick-not.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Android with OneNote Quick Notes"></p><h3>How to create a quick note from Windows&#xA0;10</h3><p>Quick notes are located in the bottom right corner. The icon will look like the OneNote symbol plus scissors.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/windows-10-onenote-icon.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Windows 10 OneNote Icon"></p><h3>How to access your quick&#xA0;notes</h3><ol><li>Open OneNote and click <strong>Quick Notes</strong>.</li></ol><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-quick-notes.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Quick Notes"></p></section><section><h2 id="2-search-across-all-yournotes">2. Search across all your&#xA0;notes</h2><p>The more you use OneNote the more content you&#x2019;ll store. It can quickly become your go to place for everything and anything. The structure of OneNote has unlimited options. If you&#x2019;re like me, you&#x2019;ll quickly forget where you stored things! Luckily the built-in search is fantastic.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-search.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Search"></p><p>OneNote can help you find notes no matter where they are. To find notes, select the magnifying glass or press Ctrl+F and type a search word or phrase. OneNote searches typed text, handwritten notes, and even words shown in pictures. If you want to narrow the search, select the drop-down arrow and choose an option. And OneNote highlights the search words in pictures and in notes. When you&#x2019;re done, select the X to close the search results.</p><p>With OneNote, find you notes wherever they are.</p></section><section><h2 id="3-share-your-notebook-and-coll">3. Share your notebook and collaborate in real-time</h2><p>OneNote&#x2019;s possibilities don&#x2019;t end with shopping lists, and personal to-do lists. In today&#x2019;s day in age, teams need to collaborate in real-time, from anywhere. OneNote notebooks can be used to keep projects organized, share notes about clients with your team, share the highlights and action items from meetings, and provide an internal Wiki to store processes.</p><p>You can invite people to see your notebook with an email message generated by OneNote. Only people who are invited will be able to open your notebook.</p><ol><li>Choose <strong>File</strong> &gt; <strong>Share</strong>.</li></ol><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-sharing.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Sharing"></p><p>2. Under <strong>Share with People</strong>, type the names or email addresses of people you&#x2019;d like to share your notebook with.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-sharing-edit-permissio.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Sharing Edit Permissions"></p><p>3. In the drop-down box on the right, choose whether each person can edit or just view your notebook.</p><p>4. Add a personal note, if you&#x2019;d like, and choose <strong>Share</strong>.<br>The people you&#x2019;ve selected will get an email invitation to open your notebook.</p></section><section><h2 id="4-draw-and-hand-write-notes-fo">4. Draw and hand write notes for&#xA0;clarity</h2><p>Sometimes computers can get in the way. Until I started using OneNote I kept a pen and paper on my desk at all times. It was easy to jot quick notes from a phone call, make a quick drawing to capture a complex idea or circle important things. In OneNote, you can type notes, write notes, convert handwritten notes to text, and even draw directly on the page.</p><p>From any OneNote page select the <strong>Draw </strong>tab in the ribbon and click your desired pen.</p></section><section><h2 id="5-use-tags-to-categorize-and-p">5. Use tags to categorize and prioritize notes</h2><p>Tags are a way to categorize and prioritize notes in OneNote 2016. With tags, you can quickly return to important items, remind yourself about action items, or filter on notes you&#x2019;d like to share with others. You can tag anything from a single line of text to an entire paragraph.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-tags.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Tags"></p><p><em>Tips: When you&#x2019;re done with a tagged note, you can remove the tag so it doesn&#x2019;t show up in tagged notes search results.</em></p><ul><li><em>To remove a single tag, right-click it, and click Remove Tag.</em></li><li><em>To remove multiple tags, select all of the text containing the tags you want to remove, and then press CTRL+0 (ZERO).</em></li></ul><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-tags-all.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Tags All"></p><p>If you&#x2019;ve previously added tags to any of your notes, you can search for the tags by using tag keywords. In OneNote 2016, the results appear in an easy-to-read summary. If you want to view the tag search results as a notes page, click the &#x201C;Create Summary Page&#x201D; button at the bottom of the Tags Summary task pane.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-tag-search.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Tag Search"></p></section><section><h2 id="6-integrate-onenote-with-outlo">6. Integrate OneNote with Outlook&#xA0;Flags</h2><p>Now, we&#x2019;re getting to OneNote&#x2019;s true potential! As you take notes and plan projects in OneNote, you might wonder how to manage deadlines and remember the things on your to-do list. One way is to create Outlook tasks. Then you can view and track those tasks in Outlook and even get reminders.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-outlook-flags.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Outlook Flags"></p><p>You can also:</p><ul><li>Find a task in OneNote.</li><li>Mark a task as complete.</li><li>Delete a task.</li></ul><p>OneNote and Outlook work together in other ways too. For example, you can manage meeting details and send notes in an email message.</p></section><section><h2 id="7-passwordprotect-yournotes">7. Password-Protect your&#xA0;Notes</h2><p>Password protection in OneNote is designed to help keep your notes safe from prying eyes. Whether you use OneNote for class notes at school, meeting notes at work, a personal diary or blog at home, or personal information about yourself or your friends and family, passwords play a crucial part in controlling access to those notes.</p><p>You can help keep your private notes safe from prying eyes by protecting a OneNote notebook section with a password. When a section is password-protected, all of its pages are locked until you enter the correct password.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-password-protect-secti.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Password Protect Section"></p><p><strong>Note</strong>: Choose your password carefully. If you forget your password, no one will be able to unlock your notes for you (not even Microsoft Technical Support).</p><p>You can also:</p><ul><li>Lock the protected sections in your notebook.</li><li>Change the password for a protected section.</li><li>Remove the password from a protected section.</li><li>Set various password protection options.</li><li>See OneNote 2016 Help (F1).</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="8-create--use-page-templates">8. Create &amp; Use Page Templates</h2><p>In OneNote, a template is a page design that you can apply to new pages in your notebook to give them an appealing background, a more uniform appearance, or a consistent layout.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-page-templates.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Page Templates"></p><p>OneNote comes with several built-in page templates that you can choose from, including decorative page backgrounds, planners, and To Do lists. If you&#x2019;d like, you can also create your own page template or customize an existing one.</p><p>Note: Many template designs include content that appears in specific places on the page. For this reason, templates in OneNote can only be applied to new pages that don&#x2019;t already contain any notes. If you want to apply a template to a page that already contains notes, first create a new page from the template you want, and then copy your existing notes over to it.</p></section><section><h2 id="9-organize-pages-withsubpages">9. Organize Pages with&#xA0;Subpages</h2><p>Subpages are a good way to group and organize notes. For example, if you have annual and monthly meeting notes, the annual meeting notes can be a main page and you can demote the monthly meeting notes so they become subpages.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-subpage-hide.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Subpage Hide"></p><p>If you have a lot of notebooks and pages and notice that it&#x2019;s getting harder to find what you&#x2019;re looking for, you can search notes and navigate results. Another way to stay efficient is by organizing your notebooks, sections, and pages.</p><p>When you move a page that has subpages, the group moves together if the subpages are collapsed. If you want to move a single subpage, promote it to a page by dragging it to the left, and then click and drag the page up or down to the location you want.</p></section><section><h2 id="10-use-onenote-as-a-teamwiki">10. Use OneNote as a Team&#xA0;Wiki</h2><p>If you&#x2019;d like to share your notebook with other people, make sure you create your OneNote 2016 notebook on OneDrive so others can get to it. If you&#x2019;ve already created a notebook on your computer, first move it to OneDrive. Just because your notebook is on OneDrive doesn&#x2019;t mean people can automatically see it. It&#x2019;s available to you on all your devices. You&#x2019;ll have to deliberately share it with others before anyone else can see it.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-sharing.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Sharing"></p><ul><li>You can generate a link to your notebook so others can view or edit it (File tab &gt; Share &gt; Get a Sharing Link). If someone forwards the link to another person, they will also be able to see your notebook.</li><li>If you ever change your mind, you can change permissions or stop sharing your notebook. It will still be on OneDrive so you can get to it on all your devices.</li></ul><p>Thanks to OneNotes tags, and search capability it becomes a great place to use as a team wiki. When shared from OneDrive or SharePoint it becomes available offline too. I recommend a SharePoint Online site for teams of ten or more.</p><h3>Tips:</h3><ul><li>Follow a specific structure. Your first OneNote page should tell users how to use and update the OneNote.</li><li>Use Tags properly. They make it easy to find to-do lists, etc.</li><li>Chose an organization structure. At TierPoint, we group our notes by application / technology. Make OneNote work for you, not the other way around.</li></ul></section><section><h2 id="11-manage-projects-throughonen">11. Manage Projects Through&#xA0;OneNote</h2><p>I manage a lot of projects through OneNote. I keep specific structures, templates, and notes for quick reuse. Here&#x2019;s my structure:</p><p>Create a section for every on going project. Name the section with the project name. Create a section group called <strong>Closed</strong>. When a project is completed, move it to the closed section.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-emptry-section.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Emptry Section"></p><p>The first page is always named the project name. It&#x2019;s a summary and where to keep important information I have to refer to often. Flag the title of the page so the project will show up in your Outlook To-do list.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-summary-page-of-a-proj.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Summary page of a project"></p><p>Then I create a page for <strong>Tasks</strong>. This list will typically be a list of things I have to do for every project like this. I&#x2019;ll create subpages with additional tasks. These are special things I need to complete for this particular project. I also create a meeting notes section. Every meeting I create a subpage with the notes from the meeting. Lastly, I&#x2019;ll create a <strong>Communications</strong> section where I dump important memos and emails that I&#x2019;ll need to reference later.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-tasks-page.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Tasks Page"></p></section><section><h2 id="12-outlook-meeting-notes">12. Outlook Meeting Notes</h2><p>OneNote is a fantastic place to store meeting notes. With simple integration into Outlook, it&#x2019;s as easy as a click of a button.</p><p>From an Outlook appointment click <strong>Meeting Notes</strong> under the <strong>Meeting</strong> ribbon.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/outlook-meeting-notes-button-f.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Outlook Meeting Notes Button for OneNote"></p><p>As the meeting organizer you can chose to share your notes with the other attendees or take private notes.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-meeting-notes-options-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Meeting Notes options. Shares notes or keep personal notes."></p><p>Next, chose the notebook and section where you want the notes to be stored.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-share-with-meeting-scr.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote share with meeting screen shot to select a location for your meeting notes."></p><p>OneNote will automatically add a ton of useful information to the OneNote page. For example, you can quickly see the time of the meeting, and it even adds check boxes so you can flag who arrived for the meeting.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-automated-meeting-note.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote automated meeting notes template."></p><p>If you chose to share the notes, a link will be automatically added to the meeting invitation. You can send a quick update and every can access your notes!</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/onenote-shared-meeting-notes-s.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="OneNote Shared Meeting Notes screen shot."></p><p>Meeting notes are a great addition to using OneNote to manage your projects.</p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/12-tips-for-improving-producti-1200x900.jpg" length="132668" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[What’s Microsoft Bookings?]]></title>
            <link>http://gitbit.org/articles/whats-microsoft-bookings</link>
            <guid>http://gitbit.org/articles/whats-microsoft-bookings</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 25 Apr 2018 01:24:32 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Microsoft has added the Microsoft Bookings app to Office 365 Enterprise (E3 & E5) customers. Bookings is an app that can simplify and automate how customers schedule and manage appointments. Originally designed for small businesses, Microsoft has continued to improve the product and has expanded the]]></description>
            <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h1>What&#x2019;s Microsoft Bookings?</h1><p>Microsoft has added the Microsoft Bookings app to Office 365 Enterprise (E3 &amp; E5) customers. Bookings is an app that can simplify and automate how customers schedule and manage appointments. Originally designed for small businesses, Microsoft has continued to improve the product and has expanded the app to enterprise customers.</p><section><h2 id="why-use-microsoft-bookings">Why use Microsoft Bookings?</h2><h3>Customers Love it!</h3><p>Customers love the flexibility and convenience they have when using Bookings. They can visit the simple Bookings webpage on any device and schedule an appointment. After scheduling an appointment, they receive a confirmation email and can reschedule, or cancel if they must. With Bookings, the process for customers and prospective customers is easy, fast, and flexible.</p><h3>Automate and Streamline Scheduling</h3><p>Bookings will help automate and streamline scheduling. Employees can setup available times, and set time off. Then customers can book their own appointments so you don&#x2019;t waste time on the phone gathering information. Bookings will keep your staff and customers coordinated, with little to no effort.</p><p>Thanks to the Office 365 integration, your staff can continue to use their Outlook calendar as usual. If a staff member schedules a meeting in their Outlook calendar, they will automatically become unavailable in Bookings. The synchronization makes adding Booking to someone&#x2019;s day simple, and easy.</p><p>When a customer books an appointment, the calendar item will automatically sync to your staff&#x2019;s calendar, so they don&#x2019;t have to go hunting for their schedules or manage their Booking calendar separate from their day to day calendar. The two-way sync is beautifully designed to keep staff and customers happy.</p><h3>Decrease No-Shows</h3><p>Decrease no-shows with automatic reminders for customers. After a customer books an appointment they&#x2019;ll receive a confirmation of their booking directly in their inbox. Customers can add their appointments to their own personal calendars to make sure they remember the appointment in their busy lives. Bookings will send a reminder email prior to the appointment.</p><h3>Easy to Use</h3><p>Managing Bookings is easy to do, even on the go. With a web app and apps for smart phones, you can keep up with customers and appointments in the office and on the go. Use the app to email, call, or text customers or even add an appointment for your customer.</p><h3>Who should use Bookings?</h3><p>Bookings is a fantastic app for most verticals. Add Bookings to your site and offer a free consultation to help your organization grow. You can also use Bookings with current customers to schedule appointments. Service organizations for example, law firms, and insurance companies are finding online scheduling a great way to help their organization grow.</p></section><section><h2 id="how-to-get-bookings">How to get Bookings</h2><p><strong>To get the free app added to your Office 365 enterprise, contact your Microsoft partner. Your partner can give you access and assign the licenses appropriately.</strong></p><h3>How to Access Bookings</h3><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-bookings-online-appo.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Bookings: Online appointments scheduling"></p><p>Access Bookings through the Office 365 App Launcher.</p><ol><li>Login to&#xA0;<a href="https://portal.office.com/">https://portal.office.com</a>&#xA0;and open the App Launcher by clicking the icon in the top right.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-365-app-launcher-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office 365 App Launcher Button"></li><li>If you don&#x2019;t see the Bookings app, click the All Apps button at the bottom.<img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/office-365-app-launcher-screen.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Office 365 App Launcher screenshot"></li><li>Find &amp; click the Bookings app.<br><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/bookings-icon.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Bookings Icon"></li></ol></section><section><h2 id="how-to-setup-bookings">How to Setup Bookings</h2><p>Your Office 365 partner should help you with the first configuration. There are a lot of different options that must be properly set prior to using the app. In this section, I&#x2019;ll try to detail the configuration as best as possible.</p><h3>Add Logo</h3><p>It&#x2019;s important to brand the site with your logo so customers feel comfortable. Add your company logo by clicking the large add logo button in the top left.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-add-logo-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screenshot of add logo button"></p><p>In the Business Logo pane, click&#xA0;<strong>Upload new logo</strong>. Upload your organizations logo. The aspect ratio should be a square and the image should be smaller than 160x160.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-the-upload-new-i.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of the upload new image button"></p><p>After uploading the image, you can change the background color. It&#x2019;s best to select a background color that will match your Bookings theme.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-background-color.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of background color options"></p><p>Click&#xA0;<strong>Save</strong>&#xA0;and your logo will appear in the Bookings website.</p><h3>Setup Business Information</h3><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/business-information-page-scre.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Business Information Page Screenshot"></p><p>Next, we&#x2019;ll need to update your business information. To setup your business information for example, company name, address, and phone number click the business information button in the bottom of the left navigation pane.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/businessinformationbutton.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="business-information-button"></p><p>Your information will appear on the Bookings web page, fill in the common fields as best as possible. The business hours will be used to limit the amount of availability someone can schedule an appointment. By default, the hours will be set to standard business hours. If you only want to accept appointments on one day a week, adjust your business hours. Staff has their own business hours too. Available hours are customizable for each employee on the Staff page too.</p><h3>How to Add Staff</h3><p>Bookings will directly link your customers and prospective customers to your staff. To add a staff member, click the Staff button in the left navigation pane.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/staff-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="staff button"></p><p>From the staff management page, you can see which staff members are connected to Bookings or quickly add and remove staff members.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-staff-management.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screenshot of staff management page"></p><p>Clicking the Add staff button at the top will open the Staff details pane.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-microsoft-bookin.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of Microsoft Bookings staff details page"></p><p>From the staff details pane, you can select a person in your company then edit their availability, add phone numbers, etc. One of the latest features has added the ability to sync Bookings availability with the person&#x2019;s calendar. If they schedule an internal meeting during their available Bookings time, the time will automatically be unavailable to customers!</p><p>Each staff can be assigned one of three roles: administrator, viewer, or guest.</p><ul><li>Administrators have full access to Bookings. They can add staff members, change any settings, etc. The administrator role should be limited to management, IT, and any employees that will manage Bookings.</li><li>Viewers can open the booking calendar but only view their own appointments. The Bookings calendar will automatically appear in an employee&#x2019;s OWA.</li><li>Guests can be assigned to bookings but can&#x2019;t open or change anything in Bookings. The appointments will automatically sync to their personal calendars. Guest access is recommended for most of the employees that handle the services.</li></ul><h3>How to Configure Services</h3><p>When someone wants to book a time with your organization, one of the first options they&#x2019;ll see is a list of services. To add services, go to the services page by clicking&#xA0;<strong>Services</strong>&#xA0;in the left navigation pane.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-showing-the-service.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screenshot showing the services option in Microsoft Bookings"></p><p>To create a new service, click the&#xA0;<strong>Add a service</strong>&#xA0;button in the top toolbar. From the Service details pane, you can easily create a service. The Service name and description will be customer facing. They should be clear enough for customers to understand what they&#x2019;re scheduling an appointment for.</p><p>Each service will have one or more staff members assigned. When scheduling an appointment, a customer can either chose a staff member or one can be automatically assigned based on availability.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-service-details-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of service details page"></p><p>Bookings does include a price option. If you set a price, the customer will see the price when selecting the service. Unfortunately, there&#x2019;s no tie in back to Office 365&#x2019;s invoicing capabilities but it&#x2019;s coming soon!</p><p>When finished save your new service.</p><h3>How to Configure the Booking Page</h3><p>The Booking page is the page customers will see when they want to book time. To edit the booking page, click the&#xA0;<strong>Booking page</strong>&#xA0;button in the left navigation.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/booking-page-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Booking Page Button"></p><p>From the Booking page you can update the theme, change the scheduling policy, and publish the site. You&#x2019;ll need to remember to save and publish your site prior to launch.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-microsoft-bookin.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of Microsoft Bookings page"></p><h3>How to Publish your Bookings Site</h3><p>Bookings won&#x2019;t be live until you publish the site. Go to the&#xA0;<strong>Booking page</strong>by clicking the&#xA0;<strong>Booking page</strong>&#xA0;button in the left navigation.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/booking-page-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Booking Page Button"></p><p>Click the&#xA0;<strong>Save and publish</strong>&#xA0;button in the top toolbar.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/save-and-publish-screenshot.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Save and Publish Screenshot"></p><p>Once published, you&#x2019;ll see a link to the site. You can share the link to customers, then they can book appointments automatically.</p><h3>How do I Publish Booking to my Website?</h3><p>If you want prospective customers to schedule appointments, we&#x2019;ll need to add the Bookings page to your site or a link to the Bookings site. Go to the&#xA0;<strong>Booking page</strong>&#xA0;by clicking the&#xA0;<strong>Booking page</strong>&#xA0;button in the left navigation.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/booking-page-button.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Booking Page Button"></p><p>Once on the Booking page, click the&#xA0;<strong>Embed</strong>&#xA0;button in the top toolbar.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/embedbutton.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="embed-button"></p><p>Microsoft will display two pieces of html code. One is a link to your booking page. The other is embeddable Iframe that can be placed directly into your website. Give this code to your web developer to add them to your site.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-microsoft-bookin.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of Microsoft Bookings embedable links"></p></section><section><h2 id="whats-the-employee-experience">What&#x2019;s the Employee Experience</h2><p>Since Bookings automatically links to your employees&#x2019; calendars, it&#x2019;s easy for your staff to stay up-to-date. If an employee schedules an appointment on their Outlook calendar they&#x2019;ll automatically be removed from the list of available staff members in Bookings. If a customer books an appointment, the employees calendar will be updated too.</p><p>When someone books an appointment without selecting a staff member, the appointment will be automatically added to one of the available employees&#x2019; calendars. The staff member will also receive an email informing them of the new appointment. The appointment will contain the customer information in case they need to reschedule or send some information prior to the engagement.</p></section><section><h2 id="whats-the-customer-experience">What&#x2019;s the Customer Experience?</h2><p>Customers can easily book time without any issues. When they go to your Booking site, they&#x2019;ll see a simple form where they can select a service, date and time and then book a request.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/schedulingscreenshot.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Scheduling-Screenshot"></p><p>After booking a time, they&#x2019;ll receive a confirmation message.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-of-confirmation-dia.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="screenshot of confirmation dialog"></p><p>Within minutes they&#x2019;ll receive a beautiful email reminding them of the appointment.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/booking-confirmation-screensho.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Booking confirmation screenshot"></p><p>The email is configured so apps like Gmail will request to put the appointment on their calendar.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screenshot-showing-google-cale.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screenshot showing Google Calendar integration"></p><p>From the email they can click Manage booking and reschedule, cancel, or create a new appointment.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/microsoft-bookings-screenshot.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Microsoft Bookings Screenshot"></p></section><section><h2 id="upcoming-features">Upcoming Features</h2><p>Microsoft is extending Bookings power by offering full control over exactly when appointments are available with customizable time increments. Customizable time increments are currently in development and expected to be released in the first half of 2018.</p><p>Multi-day and all-day bookings are currently in development and expected to be released in the first half of 2018.</p><p>The most anticipated feature is automated billing. Microsoft is developing the payment option. Once released Bookings will give the choice to request an online payment from your customers for them to complete the booking of your services. Simply setup a merchant account, add fees to your Booking services and track your payments. Payments is highly anticipated, especially for professional services for example, law firms. Automated payment processing is currently in development and expected to be released soon.</p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screen-capture-depicting-requi.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screen capture: Depicting required payment for service"></p><p><img src="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/screen-capture-showing-wepays-.png" layout="intrinsic" attribution="CC courtesy of John L. Gruber on GitBit" alt="Screen capture: Showing WePay&apos;s account management home page"></p></section>]]></content:encoded>
            <author>john.gruber@gitbit.org (John Gruber)</author>
            <enclosure url="http://gitbit.org/articles/assets/whats-microsoft-bookings-1200x900.jpg" length="69606" type ="image/jpeg">
            </enclosure>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>